# Jonathan Kerk

https://jonathankerk.com +65 9117 1996 / contact@jonathankerk.com

## **Executive Summary**

DevOps Engineer with focus on AWS cloud infrastructure and GitLab CICD. Responsible for building new and optimizing existing GitLab CICD templates, cloud resources with Terraform/Terragrunt and managing cloud infrastructure for applications hosted in AWS EKS along with other AWS technologies.

Previously a sole contributor in managing security compliances, operational costs, BAU operations of multiple AWS accounts.

Prior experiences as Systems Engineer and Software Developer / Level 2 Support. Practical scripting knowledge in Python and Bash. Proficient in Linux server administration.

### Education

University of Wollongong

Bachelor of Computer Science (Digital Systems Security) (Parttime) Oct 2018 -Mar 2021

## Skills & Competencies

Programming Languages – Python, Java, Bash, Microsoft Batch Tools – Linux, Git, GitLab CI, Terraform, Terragrunt, AWS CLI, Docker

### Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect (Associate) *SAA-C02* 

**Issued May 2022** 

## Work Experience

## Government Technology Agency

Jan 2023 - Present

- DevOps Engineer
  - Part of the Government Paid Leave Schemes (GPLS) Portal team as an individual contributor
  - Led migration of CICD workflows from Atlassin BitBucket / Bamboo to GitLab CICD
  - Architected and implemented full-fledged CICD templates and pipelines in GitLab for EKS based microservices and EC2 services, creating a workflow from source to deploy via Helm, Kubectl and Ansible.
  - Authored technical documentation for CICD templates and workflows
  - Initiated and co-hosted sharing sessions on CICD templates within and across projects
  - Migration of ~300 legacy vanilla Terraform resources to Terragrunt wrapper, along with creation of new Terraform modules
  - Championed major AWS RDS version upgrades, including drafting of technical runbook to be used by members of the team and rollout scheduling
  - Performed upgrading of AWS EKS clusters, inclusive of schedule planning, communication with team, technical runbooks
  - Led initiative to improve team's operational processes by introducing formal multiple playbooks, enforcing clear code review processes with templates to improve traceability and accountability of work
  - Initiated tracking sheet and provided initial analysis on cloud infrastructure security findings based on security reports
  - Part of operations support to provide BAU support, inclusive of OS patching via AMI refreshes, COTS software upgrades via automation and production DevOps support.
  - Prepared technical challenges and conducted technical interviews for potential candidates
  - Provided training and guidance to new and existing colleagues in DevOps / automation technologies.

### S&P Global

Jul 2022 – Jan 2023

### DevOps Engineer

- Leading infrastructure team, hosting monthly infrastructure reviews and leading discussions for improvements and optimizations
- Sole contributor in maintenance of 4 AWS Accounts, including security compliance, tagging, financial forecasting with score of 95 points based on internal metrics for all accounts
- Creation of custom Docker agent images for Mend and Sonarqube
- Integration of Product source code to corporate-hosted Mend and Sonarqube from CI pipelines

- Solutions design and implementation of cross region service for multiple AWS based products, enabling trade reporting to Hong Kong Trade Repository (HKTR)
- Implementing reusable Terraform modules for various AWS resources such as IAM Group, Users, Roles, Auto Scaling Groups, Elastic File System, Transfer
- Technical documentation for existing and new infrastructure stack
- Engagement with external vendors and corporate Cloud team on new infrastructure building blocks
- Provided technical rectifications for on-premise client, including NGINX reverseproxy configurations and security related flags

# IHS Markit (Acquired Mar 22) / S&P Global Software Developer

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022

- Contributor in Delivery team to implement enhancements and defect fixes to Spring Boot application
- Rotation-based Level 2 Support for Trade Reporting application in Spring Boot, providing in-depth troubleshooting, root cause analysis and resolution to Level 1 Support and clients
- Participated in Agile based development cycles, acting as Sprint lead for development sprints on rotation basis
- Part of infrastructure team creating and enhancing existing AWS resources using Terraform and AWS CLI
- Cost analysis of cloud billing to reduce monthly overheads, resulting in 30% cost savings in AWS operational costs by rightsizing and optimizations
- Redesigning of AWS Security Groups using Terraform modules to introduce security segregation of outbound connectivity
- Executing estate-wide deployments in for over 80 servers in UAT and Production environments
- Security and compliance fixes for AWS resources based on AWS Security Hub and internal compliance directives
- Created AWS SSM automation for refreshing AWS SES SMTP credentials for servers utilizing Postfix relay design
- Designed and implemented weekly scheduled pipeline to build custom EC2 AMIs for applications using Gitlab CI and Hashicorp Packer
- Developed automation in Lambda to identify and update AWS Auto Scaling Groups with updated AMIs built by scheduled pipelines
- Responsible for Availability-Zone scoped Disaster Recovery exercise in AWS, including drafting of proposals, execution and post mortem reports
- Authoring technical documentations for Day 2 operations for infrastructure resources in product

*Mar 2021 – Jul 2021* 

- Part of delivery team to provide enhancements to Spring application
- Performed on-site remediation of Oracle database records with SQL Procedures
- Creation of Docker database images for local integration testing for developers

### ST Engineering (Electronics) (Infosoft)

Sep 2018 - Feb 2021

Associate Engineer

- Deployment, maintenance and administration of ESXi hosts and virtualized application servers
- Administration of Microsoft Active Directory with Group Policy enforcements
- Network configuration and troubleshooting for IPv4 networks
- Providing technical consultancy and troubleshooting for on-premise systems
- Developed system report generation automation initiative in VBScript and Microsoft Batch, resulting in reduction of maintenance time cost by 90% for legacy Windows systems
- Developed Python GUI application for customizing client-based application on Windows based machines, reducing time taken for client configurations by 90% for Windows 7 systems
- Creation of golden Windows 7 images for client machines and estate-wide deployments to 700 laptops over local network
- Initiation of improved workflow by introducing on-premise Jenkins server and JFrog Artifactory for automated builds
- Assessment and maintenance of legacy Java codebases for security vulnerabilities based on HPE Fortify Static Code Analyzer